Guide to the Charles H. Hapgood Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1918-1979; Series II; 9.39; (26 boxes)
  - Children's books
    - Great Mysteries of the Earth
      - Correspondence
        - Tripp, Wallace, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 231)
      - Typescripts, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 232-235)
      - Dust jackets, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 236)
      - Reviews, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 237)
      - Arabic edition, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 238)
    - "The Little Rhinoceros", 1959, 1962, undated (Box 12, Folder 239)
  - The Earth's Shifting Crust / The Path of the Pole
    - Book production
      - Contracts and agreements, 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 240)
      - Correspondence, 1951-1968 (Box 13, Folder 241-242)
      - Popular edition, undated (Box 13, Folder 243)
      - Revisions, undated (Box 13, Folder 244)
      - Spanish article (in Mineria y Metalurgia ), 1960 (Box 13, Folder 245)
      - The Path of the Pole reviews, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - Correspondence
      - Adams, K. T.
        See: U. S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
      - American Geographical Society, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 247)
      - Anthony, Harold, 1961-1963 (Box 14, Folder 248)
      - Arnold, Larry, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 249)
      - Bain, George W., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 250)
      - Battelle Memorial Institute, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 251)
      - Bielek, Alfred D., 1956 (Box 14, Folder 252)
      - Bisque, Ramon, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 253)
      - Blanton, William W., 1961-1965 (Box 14, Folder 254)
      - Blanvalet, Lothar, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 255)
      - Brice, J. C., 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 256)
      - Briesmeister, William, 1959-1965 (Box 14, Folder 257)
      - Broms, Allan, 1961, undated (Box 14, Folder 258)
      - Brunn, J. H., 1961, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 259)
      - Carver, C. G., 1970 (Box 14, Folder 260)
      - Catipovic, Milivoj, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 261)
      - Chamalaun, T., undated (Box 14, Folder 262)
      - Connick, William, 1960-1963 (Box 14, Folder 263)
      - Coronet magazine
        Includes material on Hapgood's article on Siberian mammoths
        - Correspondence, 1959-1967 (Box 14, Folder 264)
        - Issue and fan mail, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 265)
      - Cox, Douglas, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 266)
      - Croizat, Leon, 1959 Feb 19 (Box 14, Folder 267)
      - De la Calle, Rivero, 1963 Mar 28 (Box 14, Folder 268)
      - Deiniger, Harriet, 1950-1951 (Box 14, Folder 269)
      - Deutsch, Ernst, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 270)
      - Dietz, Robert, 1961-1968 (Box 14, Folder 271)
      - Dinic, Jovan S., 1960-1963 (Box 14, Folder 272)
      - Dorman, H. C., 1963 (Box 14, Folder 273)
      - Dubois, Robert L., 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 274)
      - Dutch Geographical Society, 1958-1959 (Box 14, Folder 275)
      - Earll, F. N., 1959-1970 (Box 14, Folder 276)
      - Les Editions du Temps, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 277)
      - Editorial Letras, 1959-1972 (Box 14, Folder 278)
      - Electronics magazine, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 279)
      - Elvers, Douglas, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 280-281)
      - Emiliani, Cesare, 1954, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 282)
      - Erickson, Carl, 1961-1973 (Box 15, Folder 283)
      - Ewing, Maurice, 1952-1964 (Box 15, Folder 284)
      - Fairbridge, Rhodes, 1965 Jan 12 (Box 15, Folder 285)
      - Fate magazine, 1961-1971 (Box 15, Folder 286)
      - Fichtner, Horst, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 287)
      - Finley, Robert W., 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 288)
      - Fix, William, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 289)
      - Foundation for Integrated Education, Inc., 1946-1958 (Box 15, Folder 290-291)
      - Fuller, Mary Margaret
      - Graham, John W., 1956-1968 (Box 15, Folder 292)
      - Grossinger, Richard, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 293)
      - Gussow, William C., 1963 (Box 15, Folder 294)
      - Halgren, Charles, 1965-1968 (Box 15, Folder 295)
      - Hansen, Evan, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 296-297)
      - Harper's Magazine, 1951, undated (Box 16, Folder 298)
      - Harrison, Mary Roberts, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 299)
      - Heezen, Bruce, undated (Box 16, Folder 300)
      - Hehr, Frederick G., 1953-1965 (Box 16, Folder 301-302)
      - Heinemann, Ltd., 1958 (Box 16, Folder 303)
      - Heusser, Calvin J., 1966-1968 (Box 16, Folder 304)
      - Hough, Jack, 1953-1968 (Box 16, Folder 305)
      - Hubbert, M. King, 1956, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 306)
      - Hudson, Edward F., 1969 (Box 16, Folder 307)
      - Hunkins, Kenneth, 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 308)
      - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1951-1958 (Box 16, Folder 309-310)
      - Kirchman, R. I., 1974 (Box 16, Folder 311)
      - Kohler, Robert E.
        See: Elvers, Douglas
      - Kresz, François, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 312)
      - McFarling, Kenneth, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 313)
      - McKenzie, Robert L., 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 314)
      - McLean, Kenneth, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 315)
      - Ma, Ting Ying H., 1954-1956 (Box 16, Folder 316)
      - Main Currents in Modern Thought
        See: Foundation for Integrated Education, Inc.
      - Manciu, Ing. T., 1964 (Box 16, Folder 317)
      - Manson, Lewis A., 1978 (Box 16, Folder 318)
      - Margenau, Henry, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 319)
      - Mather, Kirtley, 1950-1971 (Box 16, Folder 320)
      - Meinesz, F. A. Vening, undated (Box 16, Folder 321)
      - Mensies, Robert J., 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 322)
      - Museum Press, 1959-1962 (Box 16, Folder 323)
      - Nature and Science, 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 324)
      - New Hampshire Educator, 1958, undated (Box 16, Folder 325)
      - Palmer, David, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 326)
      - Pauly, Karl A., 1957-1959 (Box 16, Folder 327)
      - Pfeffer, Max, 1955-1964 (Box 17, Folder 328-329)
      - Rennell of Rodd, Francis James Rennell Rodd, Baron, 1957-1959 (Box 17, Folder 330)
      - Reynolds, Barrie, 1976-1978 (Box 17, Folder 331)
      - Richardson, Edward Adams, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 332)
      - Robertson, Russell, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 333)
      - Royal Geographical Society, 1961-1963 (Box 17, Folder 334)
      - Sacriste, A., 1960 (Box 17, Folder 335)
      - Saks, V. N., 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 336)
      - Schove, A. P., 1960 Mar 26 (Box 17, Folder 337)
      - Sepic, Emil, 1965-1973 (Box 17, Folder 338)
      - Shattuck, Travis, 1962-1963 (Box 17, Folder 339)
      - Simmons, Patty, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 340)
      - Smith, Clarence, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 341)
      - Smith, Donn, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 342)
      - Smith, James V., 1959-1973 (Box 17, Folder 343)
      - Stillman, Edgar, 1967 Dec 6 (Box 17, Folder 344)
      - Tiede, Vance, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 345)
      - U. S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1950-1952 (Box 17, Folder 346)
      - Urry, William D., 1953-1954 (Box 17, Folder 347)
      - Vaughan, Alan, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 348)
      - Velikovsky, Immanuel, 1950-1956 (Box 17, Folder 349)
      - Weyer, Edward M., 1976-1978 (Box 17, Folder 350)
      - Wilson, J. Tuzo, 1963-1968 (Box 17, Folder 351)
      - Wraight, A. Joseph, 1967-1979 (Box 17, Folder 352)
      - Yes Bookstore, undated (Box 17, Folder 353)
      - Young, Arthur, 1962-1974 (Box 17, Folder 354-355)
    - Subject Files
      - Alfven, Hannes, 1963 May 11 (Box 18, Folder 356)
      - Antarctic Ice Age, 1964-1968 (Box 18, Folder 357-358)
      - Arctic Ocean, 1954, 1957, undated
      - Arrhenius, Gustaf O. S., 1958-1966 (Box 18, Folder 359)
      - Astrolabe, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 360)
      - Bascom, Willard, circa 1965
      - Centrifugal effect, 1918-1958 (Box 18, Folder 361)
      - Climate change, 1950-1958, undated (Box 18, Folder 362)
      - "Continental Dynamics," by Melvin A. Cook, 1961 Jan 31 (Box 18, Folder 363)
      - Cosmic rays, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 364)
      - Earth as triaxial ellipsoid, 1949-1959 (Box 18, Folder 365)
      - Earthquakes, 1950-1969 (Box 18, Folder 366)
      - Earth's rotation, 1951-1967, undated (Box 18, Folder 367)
      - Geomagnetism
        - General information, 1943-1966 (Box 18, Folder 368-372)
        - Student papers, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 373)
      - Hawaii, 1962 Nov 23 (Box 19, Folder 374)
      - Hopi Nation, 1976, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 375)
      - Human story, undated (Box 19, Folder 376)
      - Ice Age, 1923, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 377)
      - Ice Age article, undated (Box 19, Folder 378-379)
      - Japan geology, 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 380)
      - Moho, 1959, 1964
      - Moon landings, 1964, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 381)
      - "The Mystery of the Oldest Map of Antarctica", circa 1970 (Box 19, Folder 382)
      - Physics, 1973, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 383)
      - "Pole Watchers' Newsletter", 1969-1971 (Box 19, Folder 384)
      - Radiocarbon notes, undated (Box 19, Folder 385)
      - Rennell artifacts, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 386)
      - Science, general, 1950-1963 (Box 19, Folder 387)
      - Sea levels, 1951-1967 (Box 19, Folder 388)
      - Sea mountain, 1959 Jan 18 (Box 19, Folder 389)
      - "Shifting Continents: A Coming World Catastrophe..." in Argosy magazine, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 390)
      - Smithsonian Institution, Center for Short-lived Phenomena, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 391)
      - Society for the Investigation of the Unexplained (SITU), 1969-1971 (Box 20, Folder 392-393)
      - Terrestrial magnetism, 1955, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 394)
      - Time scale, 1958-1963 (Box 20, Folder 395)
      - Tornadoes, 1951, 1953
      - The Ultimate Frontier book review, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 396)
      - Watkins, N. D., 1968, undated (Box 20, Folder 397)
      - Wisconsin glacier, 1958-1963 (Box 20, Folder 398)
  - Maps of the Ancient Sea Kings
    - Book production
      - General correspondence, 1924-1978 (Box 21, Folder 399-403)
        Filed chronologically
      - Book manuscript, undated (Box 21, Folder 404-409)
      - Notes and drafts, 1962-1964, undated (Box 22, Folder 410)
      - Reviews, 1964-1966 (Box 22, Folder 411)
      - Revisions, 1964-1966 (Box 22, Folder 412)
      - Revisions, 1973-1979 (Box 22, Folder 413-415)
    - Correspondence
      - Abrons, Stanley, 1957-1960 (Box 23, Folder 416)
      - Allen, Margery, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 417)
      - Ambassador College, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 418)
      - Bancroft, Marjorie, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 419)
      - Benedict, Herbert, 1962-1964 (Box 23, Folder 420)
      - Bibliotheque Nationale, 1960-1964 (Box 23, Folder 421)
      - Bohomolec, A., 1967 (Box 23, Folder 422)
      - Brown, Lloyd A., undated (Box 23, Folder 423)
      - Burroughs, Lorenzo W., 1960-1966 (Box 23, Folder 424-425)
      - Capps, Isabelle, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 426)
      - Carter, George, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 427)
      - Cinis, Philip H., 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 428)
      - Cortesao, Armando, 1953-1966 (Box 23, Folder 429)
      - De Santillana, Giorgio, 1962-1970 (Box 23, Folder 430)
      - Dufek, George, 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 431)
      - Dinu, Dimitru, 1969 Sep 16 (Box 23, Folder 432)
      - Earley, George, 1963-1968 (Box 23, Folder 433)
      - Ericson, David, 1948-1963 (Box 23, Folder 434-435)
      - Evans, Gordon H., 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 436)
      - Farnham, John R., 1969 (Box 23, Folder 437)
      - Fleming, Randy and Rosemary, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 438)
      - Fraley, Francis, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 439)
      - Fuller, R. Buckminster, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 440)
      - Georgetown University Forum, 1957-1959
        See: Correspondence
      - Gerlach, Arch C., 1961-1963 (Box 23, Folder 441)
      - Goes, J. G. Peter, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 442)
      - Gordon, Cyrus H., 1957-1974 (Box 23, Folder 443-444)
      - Gove, Sidney, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 445)
      - Gray, W. F., 1963 May 14 (Box 24, Folder 446)
      - Hawkins, Gerald, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 447)
      - Hemmingsen, Erik, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 448)
      - Heyden, Francis, 1957-1963 (Box 24, Folder 449)
      - Hispanic Society, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 450)
      - Hitchcock, Charles, 1962-1963 (Box 24, Folder 451)
      - Ho, Robert, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 452)
      - Homet, Marcel F., 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 453)
      - Horan, Edward, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 454)
      - Kadath, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 455)
      - Kamitchis, Peter, 1960 Mar 16 (Box 24, Folder 456)
      - Keansley, John, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 457)
      - Kendall, Elizabeth, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 458)
      - Keyhoe, Donald, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 459)
      - Lee, Thomas E., 1963 (Box 24, Folder 460)
      - Library of Congress, 1958-1967 (Box 24, Folder 461-462)
      - Life magazine, 1954-1961 (Box 24, Folder 463)
      - Linehan, Daniel, 1958-1964 (Box 24, Folder 464)
      - Link, Edwin A., 1959 (Box 24, Folder 465)
      - McGowan, Harold, 1966 Nov 4 (Box 24, Folder 466)
      - Mallery, Arlington H.
        - Correspondence, 1953-1964 (Box 24, Folder 467)
        - Georgetown University Forum broadcast transcript publication, 1956 Aug 26 (Box 24, Folder 468-469)
      - Morison, Samuel E., 1960-1973 (Box 24, Folder 470)
      - Misisco, Paul, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 471)
      - Mitchell, G. Wiley, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 472)
      - Murchie, Guy, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 473)
      - Ohlmeyer, Harold
        See: Burroughs, Lorenzo W.
      - Oldbourne Press, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 474)
      - Polacek, Vladimir B., 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 475)
      - Prindle, Dean, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 476)
      - Robertson, Archibald F., 1958-1960 (Box 25, Folder 477)
      - Rockefeller University, 1967r (Box 25, Folder 478)
      - Shelley, John K., 1979 (Box 25, Folder 479)
      - Stecchini, Livio C., 1966-1972 (Box 25, Folder 480)
      - Stephenson, Richard, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 481)
      - Tingleaf, Elfriede, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 482)
      - Tobler, Waldo R., 1966 (Box 25, Folder 483)
      - Todericiu, Doru, 1966 -1967 (Box 25, Folder 484)
      - United States, Air Force, Reconnaissance Technical Squadron, 8th
      - United States, Hydrographic Office, 1958-1962 (Box 25, Folder 485)
      - Vance, Adrian, 1973, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 486)
      - White, John W., 1977-1979 (Box 25, Folder 487)
      - Wright, John K., 1966 (Box 25, Folder 488)
    - Subject files
      - "Ancient Knowledge of America and Antarctica", 1963 (Box 26, Folder 489)
      - Ancient metallurgy, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 490)
      - Andrea Benincasa portolano of 1508, 1964, undated (Box 26, Folder 491)
      - The Atlantic before the later Middle Ages, undated (Box 26, Folder 492)
      - Behaim globe, undated (Box 26, Folder 493)
      - Cape Verde islands, undated (Box 26, Folder 494)
      - Cartography, undated (Box 26, Folder 495)
      - Chinese map, undated (Box 26, Folder 496)
      - DeCanerio map, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 497)
      - Dolphins, 1958, undated (Box 26, Folder 498)
      - Dulchert portolano of 1339, undated (Box 26, Folder 499)
      - Early charts, undated (Box 26, Folder 500)
      - Gold, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 501)
      - Hudson, G. F., undated (Box 26, Folder 502)
      - Kahle, Paul, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 503)
      - Longitude, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 504)
      - "Lost Maps of Ancient Crete", undated (Box 26, Folder 505)
      - Mammoths, undated (Box 26, Folder 506)
      - Map projections, undated (Box 26, Folder 507)
      - Mercator's maps, 1963, undated (Box 26, Folder 508)
      - Mystery Hill, New Hampshire, 1967-1971 (Box 26, Folder 509)
      - Oronteus Finaeus map, 1964, undated (Box 26, Folder 510)
      - Osmundsen research, 1963-1967 (Box 26, Folder 511)
      - Piri Reis map
        - Afetinan book and class handout, 1954, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 512)
        - Fitting the map to the globe, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 513)
        - General information, 1933-1968, undated (Box 26, Folder 514)
        - Inscriptions, 1961, undated (Box 26, Folder 515)
        - Notes, undated (Box 26, Folder 516)
        - Tables, 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 517)
      - Portolan grid, undated (Box 26, Folder 518)
      - Projections, undated (Box 26, Folder 519)
      - "The Rediscovery of the Cartography of Ancient Phoenicia", 1964 (Box 26, Folder 520)
        Paper read at the New England Academy of Science, May 16, 1964
      - Shipbuilding, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 521)
  - Psychic Studies
    - Correspondence
      - Aharon, Ibn Y. N., 1958-1961 (Box 27, Folder 522)
      - AUM Study Center, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 523)
      - Babbitt, Elwood, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 524)
      - Backster, Cleve, 1969-1978 (Box 27, Folder 525)
      - Beckmann, Jon
        See: Hawthorn Books, Inc.
      - Berzin, Alex, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 526)
      - Carpenter, David, 1969-1974, undated (Box 27, Folder 527-528)
      - Carton, John, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 529)
      - Cook, Charles, 1964-1973 (Box 27, Folder 530)
      - Cooke, John, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 531)
      - Dixon, Jeane L., 1963-1966 (Box 27, Folder 532)
      - Dirksen, Everett, Mrs., 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 533)
      - Farnham, Edwin, 1975 Jan 10 (Box 27, Folder 534)
      - Foley Agency, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 535)
      - Fortner, Yonah N.
        See: Aharon, Ibn Y. N.
      - Gerald, Antonia, 1976 Dec 5 (Box 27, Folder 536)
      - Grasslander, Karl, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 537)
      - Green, Chris, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 538)
      - Greenhouse, Herbert B., 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 539)
      - Haber, Jon, 1977-1979 (Box 27, Folder 540)
      - Hart, Ann, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 541)
      - Hawthorn Books, Inc., 1970-1972 (Box 27, Folder 542)
      - Hill, Raymond P., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 543)
      - Jaques, Pat and Phyllis, 1976-1979 (Box 27, Folder 544)
      - Kimball, Edna, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 545)
      - Lidden, Sim C., 1969 (Box 27, Folder 546)
      - Lunan, Duncan, 1977 Feb 9 (Box 27, Folder 547)
      - Lyons, Kenneth M., 1967 (Box 27, Folder 548)
      - Manning, Daniel, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 549)
      - Miyereck, Randy, undated (Box 27, Folder 550)
      - National Enquirer, 1977 Apr 23 (Box 27, Folder 551)
      - Nelson, Daria, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 552)
      - Newhall, H. R., 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 553)
      - Osis, Karlis, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 554)
      - Puharich, Andrija, 1971 Jan 30 (Box 27, Folder 555)
      - Remey, Charles Mason, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 556)
      - Russell, Edward W., 1973-1975 (Box 27, Folder 557)
      - Simon & Schuster, Inc., 1954-1973 (Box 27, Folder 558)
      - Smith, Mary B., 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 559)
      - Steiger, Brad, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 560)
      - Stern, Herman Lee, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 561)
        Includes snapshot photograph of Stern with Albert Einstein
      - Sullivan, William, 1976-1978 (Box 27, Folder 562)
      - Swanson, Darlene, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 563)
      - Tomlin, Fred and Mary, 1971-1978 (Box 28, Folder 564)
      - Turner, J. Richard, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 565)
      - Tuton, Charlotte, 1974-1979 (Box 28, Folder 566)
      - Voiceprint Laboratories
        - Correspondence, 1969-1977 (Box 28, Folder 567)
        - Recording, 1/4 inch magnetic tape, undated (Box 28, Folder 568)
        - Spectrograph printouts (voiceprints), [1969?] (Box 28, Folder 569)
      - Wiklind, Daria, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 570)
      - Willis, Paul, 1972-1974 (Box 28, Folder 571)
      - Winn, Frank, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 572)
    - Spirit communications
      - Amos (Biblical prophet), 1971 Feb 1 (Box 29, Folder 573)
      - Armstrong, Louis, 1972 Sep 16 (Box 29, Folder 574)
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne
        See: Twain, Mark
      - Cole, Jim, 1968-1972 (Box 29, Folder 575)
      - Cushing, Richard James, Cardinal, undated (Box 29, Folder 576)
      - Edison, Thomas Alva, 1972 Jan 16 (Box 29, Folder 577)
      - Einstein, Albert, 1967-1976 (Box 29, Folder 578)
      - Elizabeth I, Queen of England, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 579)
      - Father Michael, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 580)
      - Fisher, Frederick [Bishop Frederick B. Fisher?], 1969-1977 (Box 29, Folder 581-582)
      - Freud, Sigmund, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 583)
      - Gabriel (Archangel), 1967 (Box 29, Folder 584)
      - Gardner, Erle Stanley, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 585)
      - Gandhi, Mahatma, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 586)
      - Hubbard, Elbert, undated (Box 29, Folder 587)
      - Jesus Christ
        - Communications, 1967-1974 (Box 29, Folder 588)
        - Essays for book, 1972-1978, undated (Box 29, Folder 589-590)
        - Notes, 1977, undated (Box 29, Folder 591)
      - John, the Baptist, Saint, 1967 Nov 19 (Box 30, Folder 592)
      - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1973 Mar 18 (Box 30, Folder 593)
      - Judy, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 594)
      - Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1967-1973 (Box 30, Folder 595)
      - Krishna (Hindu deity), 1970-1978, undated (Box 30, Folder 596)
      - Lincoln, Abraham, 1967 Aug 18 (Box 30, Folder 597)
      - Locius, 1977 May 1 (Box 30, Folder 598)
      - Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1972 Mar 1 (Box 30, Folder 599)
      - Luke, Saint, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 600)
      - Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 601)
      - Mills, James Porter
        - Communications, 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 602-603)
        - Copyright issues, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 604)
        - Pilate, Pontius, 1st cent., 1970-1974 (Box 30, Folder 605)
      - Nixon, Richard, 1973 Jul 1 (Box 30, Folder 606)
      - Nostradamus, 1967, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 607-608)
      - Pike, James A. (James Albert), 1967-1973 (Box 30, Folder 609)
      - Shaw, Herbert, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 610)
      - Socrates, 1972-1975 (Box 30, Folder 611)
      - Stevenson, Adlai, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 612)
      - Twain, Mark, 1969-1973 (Box 31, Folder 613-617)
      - Wordsworth, William, 1967 Jul 9 (Box 31, Folder 618)
    - Subject files
      - Affirmations, prayers, invocations, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 619)
      - Animal experiments, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 620)
      - Astral flight, undated (Box 32, Folder 621)
      - AUM Study Center, 1974-1974 (Box 32, Folder 622-623)
      - Babbitt, Elwood, hospital tests, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 624)
      - Backster, Cleve, 1968-1969 (Box 32, Folder 625-626)
      - Biological field theory, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 627)
      - The Brotherhood of Light, 1978-1979 (Box 32, Folder 628)
        Includes issues of their "Light Messenger"
      - Buddha, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 629)
      - Cayce, Edgar, 1960-1977 (Box 32, Folder 630)
      - Croiset the Clairvoyant, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 631)
      - Dickens, Charles, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 632)
      - Extrasensory perception (ESP): student papers, 1965-1966, undated (Box 32, Folder 633-634)
      - Franklin, Benjamin, 1967-1972 (Box 33, Folder 635)
      - Geller, Uri, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 636)
      - Ghose, Aurobindo, 1974, undated (Box 33, Folder 637)
      - Henderson, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 638)
      - Hurkos, Peter, 1961-1964, undated (Box 33, Folder 639)
      - Hypnosis, 1965-1966, undated (Box 33, Folder 640)
      - LSD (Drug), 1972, 1978
      - Metelica, Michael, 1969-1971, undated (Box 33, Folder 641)
      - Mills, James Porter, undated (Box 33, Folder 642)
        Contains photocopy of his book, From Existence to Life: the Science of Self-Consciousness, 4th edition (1916)
      - The moon, undated (Box 33, Folder 643)
      - Movie script, undated (Box 33, Folder 644)
      - Murphy, Cynthia Huntington, undated (Box 33, Folder 645)
      - Newbrough, John Ballou, undated (Box 33, Folder 646)
      - Plant experiments, 1962-1965 (Box 33, Folder 647-648)
      - Pompano, Joe, 1972 May 8 (Box 33, Folder 649)
      - Prophecy, 1970-1975, undated (Box 34, Folder 650)
        See also: Gauger, Edgar
      - Psychical research, 1961-1968, undated (Box 34, Folder 651-652)
        See also: Society for Psychical Research
      - Religious groups, 1973, undated
      - Serios, Ted, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 653)
      - Silva Mind Control, 1969, undated (Box 34, Folder 654)
      - Sleeping Lucy, undated (Box 34, Folder 655)
      - Society for Psychical Research, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 656)
      - Split personality, 1973, undated (Box 34, Folder 657)
      - The Stelle Group, 1971-1975 (Box 34, Folder 658)
        Contains issues of the "Stelle Letter"